Felix Kusman Photographs ALBA.PHOTO.178
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Felix Kusman Photographs
1939-2003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Kusman, Felix, 1909-1983
Kusman, Helen
ALBA.PHOTO.178
2.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
Scope and Contents
The collection contains approximately 150 b&w photos, most mounted on 16 loose scrapbook pages. Almost all are from the SCW and include combat and non-combat images of shelled cities. There are also several of anti-fascist demonstrations in NYC, post WWII, including one of the VALB contingent in the 1946 May Day parade.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Kusman, Helen
- Photographs
  - General Photographs, undated
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Photocopy, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "A", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "B", undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "C", undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "D", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "E", undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "F", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "G", undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "H", undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "I", undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "J", undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "K", undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "L", undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "M", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "N", undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "O", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "P", undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "Q", undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "R", undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "S", undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "T", undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "U", undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "V", undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade - Felix Kusman Scrapbook - Page "W", undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Abraham Lincoln Brigade in Spain, Lose Photographs Found with Scrapbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - General Photographs, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Photographs, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Photographs, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - General Photographs, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - General Photographs, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - General Photographs, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - General Photographs - Demonstration (May Day Parade ?), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - General Photographs - Gerhart Eisler, Lem Harris, Felix Kusman, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - General Photographs - [May Day Parade 1939 or 1940], 1940s? (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - General Photographs, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - General Photographs, 1940s? (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - General Photographs, 1940s? (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - General Photographs, 1940s? (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - General Photographs, 1940s? (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - General Photographs, 1940s? (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - General Photographs, 1940S? (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - General Photographs, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - General Photographs - Felix Kusman, Moe Fishman and Veterans of Abraham Lincoln Brigade (possible VALB Office), 1950s (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - General Photographs - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB,) 20th Anniversay Celebration, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - General Photographs, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - General Photographs, 1950s? (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - General Photographs, 1950s? (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - General Photographs, 1950s? (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - General Photographs, 1950s? (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - General Photographs, 1950s? (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - General Photographs, 1950s? (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - General Photographs, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - General Photographs, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - General Photographs, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - General Photographs, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - General Photographs, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - General Photographs, 1960s? (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - General Photographs, 1960s? (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - General Photographs, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - General Photographs, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - General Photographs, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - General Photographs, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - General Photographs, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - General Photographs, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - General Photographs, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - General Photographs, Cuba Photos, Helen Kusman's Trip, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - General Photographs, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - General Photographs, 1970s? (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - General Photographs, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - General Photographs, 1980s? (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - General Photographs, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - General Photographs, 1990s? (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - General Photographs, 2000s (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Cuba flag (Box Tamiment Shared OS006)
    - Group photo, 1985 (Box Shared Tamiment 032)
  - Portraits
    - Portraits - Felix Kusman, undated (Box Tamiment Shared OS006, Folder 1, Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Portraits - Friends and Family, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Estonian Family and Friends
    - Group Photographs and Portraits, dated, 1939-2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Group Photographs and Portraits, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Slides and Negatives
  - Miscellaneous Negatives, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Slides - Felix and Helen Kusman and Family, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Slides - Protests and Demonstrations, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Slides - Trip to Estonia, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Slides - Vietnam War, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Slides - Helen Kusman's Trip to Cuba, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Janas Zalesky Posters, 1963-1986 (Flat-file-folder 8)
- Unprocessed materials (Box 8)
- Unprocessed International Women's Year Poster, 1975 (Flat-file-folder 1)